Finding aid for the Wanda Coleman papers LSC.2282
UCLA Library Special Collections
Wanda Coleman papers
1960-2013
UCLA Library Special Collections
Coleman, Wanda
LSC.2282
75.2 linear feet (182 boxes, 2 record cartons, and 1 flat box)
56 linear feet (44 unprocessed record cartons, 4 unprocessed flat boxes, 1 unprocessed oversize record carton, 2 unprocessed oversize boxes, 1 unprocessed document box)
168 audiovisual carriers (157 audiocassettes, 6 videocassettes, 5 records)
101 born-digital carriers (69 optical discs, 32 floppy disks)
Wanda Coleman was born on November 13, 1946 and grew up in the Watts neighborhood of Los Angeles, CA. Coleman's poetry is widely anthologized and published, and her poetry collection Bathwater Wine received the 1999 Lenore Marshall Poetry Prize. In addition to her poetic career, Coleman was also successful across genres. She had a well-known column in the Los Angeles Times and won an Emmy for her writing on Days of Our Lives. The collection contains work produced by Coleman between 1960 and 2013, including manuscripts and drafts of her published poetry and prose, journalism, writing for film and television, and spoken word recordings, as well as many unpublished writings. In addition, there is a wealth of correspondence with major literary figures and institutions, activist materials, and ephemera relating to Coleman's professional and personal life.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Originals in box 184 not available for consultation due to poor physical condition, use digitized versions only.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS UNPROCESSED DIGITAL/AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Digital/audiovisual materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email AskLSC@library.ucla.edu.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Austin Straus, 2015.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9980033763606533
Biographical / Historical
Wanda Coleman was born on November 13, 1946 in Watts and raised in South Central Los Angeles. When she was eighteen, she married her first husband, Jerry Coleman, with whom she had two children, Anthony and Luanda Tunisia. Coleman retained custody of the children when she and Jerry divorced in 1969, and struggled to survive and write as a single mother. She worked as an editor for Players, a conscious Black gentleman's magazine, from 1972-1974, and in the mid 1970s, she moved to Hollywood, where she became an active participant in the spoken word and poetry communities, penning works for Studio Watts and becoming a fixture at Beyond Baroque in Venice. In 1977, she published a chapbook, Art in the Court of the Blue Fag, followed by a full-length collection of poems, Mad Dog Black Lady (1979) with Black Sparrow Press, beginning a publishing relationship that would last for over thirty years and produce twelve books in various genres. Her third child, Ian, with her second husband Stephen Grant, was born in 1978. Coleman was also an acclaimed performance artist known for her impactful readings. In the 1980s, her presence in the LA spoken word scene led her to collaborate with seminal punk figures such as Exene Cervenka (X) and Lydia Lunch, and she worked with New Alliance records to release a number of solo and split recordings. Coleman attended Valley Junior College and Cal State L.A., and went on to teach at UCLA extension, Cal State Long Beach, Naropa, and Loyola Marymount University, where she held the Fletcher Jones chair in literature and writing. Prolific across genres, Coleman wrote poetry, short stories, novels, nonfiction, and plays, as well as scripts for film and television, winning an Emmy for her work on on Days of Our Lives in 1976 and working as a featured columnist for the Los Angeles Times. Coleman is one of the most widely anthologized and published poets of her generation, appearing in prestigious collections such as Postmodern American Poetry: A Norton Anthology and The Oxford Anthology of African-American Poetry. Her poetry collection Bathwater Wine received the 1999 Lenore Marshall Poetry Prize, Mercurochrome: New Poems (2001) was a finalist for the National Book Award, and her honors include a Guggenheim, an NEA fellowship, and the Poetry Society of America's Shelley Memorial Award. With her husband of thirty years, poet and visual artist Austin Straus, she hosted "The Poetry Connexion" on KPFK from 1981-1994. She died November 22, 2013. In November of 2015, the Ascot branch of the Los Angeles public library in Watts, where Coleman spent many of her formative years reading and writing, was renamed the Wanda Coleman Branch in her honor.
Scope and Content
The collection chronicles Coleman's entire career (1960-2013), and includes many materials that provide insight into her process, such as meticulously kept records of submissions, publications, and rejections; multiple drafts and revisions of poems, stories, and articles with Coleman's edits; correspondence with John Martin at Black Sparrow Press regarding major works; a wealth of correspondence with major literary figures such as E. Ethelbert Miller and Sesshu Foster; many activist materials; flyers and other ephemera related to Coleman's public performances and other "gigs"; teaching materials; photographs; recordings; and many unpublished writings including a novel, a collection of newer short stories, and screenplays.
Organization and Arrangement
Series 1: Correspondence, 1960-2013
Series 2: Works by Wanda Coleman, 1961-2012
Subseries 2.1: Poetry, 1968-2010
Subseries 2.2: Fiction, 1975-2012
Subseries 2.3: Nonfiction, 1973-2012
Subseries 2.4: Spoken Word, TV, Film, and Theater, 1970-2011
Subseries 2.5: Juvenilia and Visual Art, 1961-1998
Series 3: Gigs/PR, 1969-2007
Series 4: Memorabilia, 1963-2012
Collection is primarily ordered chronologically.
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital reproductions of materials in Box 184 are available for viewing in the Library Special Collections reading room.
Related Material
Black Sparrow Press records, UC Berkeley Bancroft Library (Collection BANC MSS 97/40 c).
S.A. Griffin collection of underground poetry, Scott Wannberg, and the Carma Bums, circa 1950-2015, UCLA Special Collections (Collection 2248).
John Martin Papers, 1966-1981(Collection 1267).
Watts Writers' Workshop stories, lesson books, and other material (Collection 0177).
African American women poets -- 20th century -- Archives.; African American women authors -- 20th century -- Archives.; Coleman, Wanda -- Archives
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1960-2013
  Scope and Content
  Contains personal and professional letters and emails to and from Coleman, as well as correspondence and materials detailing her submissions process and rejections/acceptances. Includes letters to and from John Martin, her publisher at Black Sparrow Press, and correspondence with major figures such as Amiri Baraka, Sherman Alexie, Octavia Butler, Exene Cervenka, Cornelius Eady, Sesshu Foster, S.A. Griffin, Allen Ginsberg, C.S. Giscombe, Anna Halprin (San Francisco Dancers' Workshop), Terrance Hayes, bell hooks, Yusef Komunyakaa, Audre Lorde, Clarence Major, E. Ethelbert Miller, Ishmael Reed, Diane Wakoski, and Anne Waldman.
  Organization and Arrangement
  Series maintains original order. Coleman organized the bulk of her personal and professional correspondence alphabetically, but the latter part of the series includes correspondence not included within this alphabetical arrangement, ordered chronologically and by type. Correspondence with major individuals and institutions has been gathered throughout processing and is included within the alphabetical sequence.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  SERIES CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. To review these audiovisual materials, you must notify the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk in advance of your visit.
  SOME ITEMS IN THIS SERIES HAVE BEEN DIGITIZED. Please contact the reference desk for details on arranging access.
  - Correspondence: A, 1985-2011 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Abee, Steve-African American Review, 1992-2010 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: AK-AL, 1987-2012 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Includes letter to John Martin (Black Sparrow Press) regarding Will Alexander and correspondence with Jeffrey Renard Allen.
  - Correspondence: AL-Another Chicago Magazine, 1987-2013 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Another Chicago Magazine-AR, 1988-2012 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Maya Angelou Controversy, 2002-2003 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    Contains correspondence to and from Coleman regarding her controversial 2002 review of Angelou's A Song Flew Up to Heaven, along with drafts of her essay on the public's response, "Black on Black: Fear and Reviewing in Los Angeles."
  - Correspondence: AR-Amiri Baraka, 1985-2013 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Art on Saturdays, 1981-1999 (Box 53, Folder 1-3)
    Scope and Contents
    Coleman did all the secretarial work for her brother George Evans' A.R.T. workshop for high schoolers. She used the pseudonym "Joyce Grant," (a combination of her middle name and her second husband's last name).
  - Correspondence: BA-BE, 1975-2013 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: BE-Beyond Baroque, 1987-2012 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Beyond Baroque-BL, 1981-2009 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: BL, 1978-2003 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Black Sparrow Press, 1971-2001 (Box 42, Folder 1-6)
  - Correspondence: BO, 1995-2003 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Includes correspondence with Laurel Ann Bogen.
  - Correspondence: BO-BR, 1985-2009 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Includes correspondence with Malcolm Boyd.
  - Correspondence: Kate Braverman-Priscilla Ann Brown, 1977-2006 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Priscilla Ann Brown (Interview), 2002 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Priscilla Ann Brown, 2002-2004 (Box 50, Folder 6-7)
    Contains drafts of and correspondence regarding Brown's 2002 interview with Coleman, published in Callaloo.
  - Correspondence: BR-BU, 1990-2006 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Includes correspondence with Jericho Brown and Fred Burkhart and emails regarding Charles Bukowski.
  - Correspondence: Sha-Ron Buie, 1997-1999 (Box 49, Folder 6-7)
  - Correspondence: BU-Caliban, 1986-2012 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: CA, 1985-2013 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Callaloo, 1981-2009 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Bliss Carnochan, 1968-2011 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: CA-CH, 1979-2012 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Includes correspondence with and ephemera relating to Exene Cervenka (X).
  - Correspondence: Wes Christensen, 1992-2012 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: CH, 1988-2013 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Includes correspondence with Marilyn Chin.
  - Correspondence: CI-Michelle T. Clinton, 1990-2005 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Michelle T. Clinton (blurb), 1985-1986 (Box 164, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: City of Los Angeles Artist Fellowship, 2003-2004 (Box 52, Folder 4-5)
    Coleman's application to and correspondence regarding the City of Los Angeles Artists' Fellowships (she was the first writer to be awarded one).
  - Correspondence: CL-CO, 1992-2003 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Includes letters to Bill Clinton.
  - Correspondence: Cleveland State University, 2005-2006 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: CO, 1985-2006 (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
    Includes correspondence relating to Jayne Cortez memorial panel.
  - Correspondence: CR-DA, 1983-2011 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Includes correspondence with Jim Cushing (Dr. Punk).
  - Correspondence: DA-DL, 1981-2011 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Includes letter to Kwame Dawes and correspondence with Fred Dewey (Beyond Baroque).
  - Correspondence: DI-DU, 1986-2012 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Djerassi Foundation, 1989-1992 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: EA-ES, 1984-2011 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Includes letter to Cornelius Eady and correspondence with C.S. Giscombe and David Lehman regarding Epoch Magazine.
  - Correspondence: ES-EV, 1975-2013 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Includes correspondence with family members (Evans).
  - Correspondence: EV-FE, 1984-2011 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Renard Faroux (France trip), 2005-2009 (Box 53, Folder 5-6)
  - Correspondence: FE-FO, 1991-2005 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Includes correspondence with Susannah Foster.
  - Correspondence: Sesshu Foster, 1986-2009 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: FO-FU, 1986-2008 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: FU-GA, 1995-2010 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: GA-GE, 1993-2009 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Joel Gersmann, 1993-2013 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: GE-GI, 1994-2011 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Includes correspondence with Allen Ginsberg and C.S. Giscombe; materials related to Ginsberg Memorial Celebration.
  - Correspondence: GL-GO, 2000-2013 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Includes correspondence with David R. Godine, the publisher who took over Black Sparrow titles after the press shut down.
  - Correspondence: Godine, 2002-2005 (Box 116, Folder 2-3)
  - Correspondence: Fred Glienna and Nanette McLane, 2006-2013 (Box 8, Folder 5, Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: GO-GR, 1986-2013 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Includes correspondence with Stephen Grant, Coleman's former husband.
  - Correspondence: GR-GU, 1977-2010 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Includes correspondence with S.A. Griffin.
  - Correspondence: S.A. Griffin (book blurb), 2001 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    Contains a packet of S.A. Griffin's poems.
  - Correspondence: HA, 1988-2012 (Box 9, Folder 4-5)
    Includes correspondence with Marilyn Hacker.
  - Correspondence: HA-Lee Hickman, 1979-2008 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Includes correspondence with Odie Hawkins, Eloise Klein Healy, and Lee Hickman.
  - Correspondence: Anna Halprin (San Francisco Dancers' Workshop), 1969-2006 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: High Performance-HI, 1986-2002 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Jack Hirschman, 1981 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    Contains correspondence with Jack Hirschman regarding a reading he and Coleman gave at Beyond Baroque, along with Wanda's set list of poems and event flyers.
  - Correspondence: HI-HO, 1985-2010 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: bell hooks-HU, 1985-2004 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: HY-International Black Writers and Artists, 1993-2005 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: International Black Writers and Artists-IV, 1983-2013 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: JA-JE, 1985-2011 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Billy Jones (Bones), 1979-2012 (Box 11, Folder 5-6, Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: JI-JO, 1988-2009 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: JU-KA, 1985-2008 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Pamala Karol (La Loca), 1988-2006 (Box 12, Folder 3-4)
  - Correspondence: Kerouac Connection (Greg Zobel), 1994-2004 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: KA-Stephen Kessler, 1981-2011 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Stephen Kessler, 1978-2013 (Box 13, Folder 1-5, Box 55, Folder 1, Box 14, Folder 1-3)
  - Correspondence: Stephen Kessler (book blurb), 1999 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: KI-KN, 1986-2007 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: KO, 1980-2006 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    Includes correspondence with Yusef Komunyakaa and Ishmael Reed (Konch magazine).
  - Correspondence: KO-KU, 1983-2011 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: LA, 1991-2000 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Jeff Land, 1989-2011 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Jeff Land-LA Weekly, 1981-2004 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: LE, 1986-2011 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    Includes correspondence with Les Figues Press.
  - Correspondence: Adam Leipzig (Artists' Circle), 1997-1999 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: LE-LI, 1987-2011 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Steve Light, 2000-2002 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: LI-LO, 1989-2011 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: LO, 1977-2009 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    Includes correspondence with Audre Lorde.
  - Correspondence: Philomene Long, 2000-2002 (Box 17, Folder 1, Box 16, Folder 4-5)
  - Correspondence: LO-LY, 1990-2010 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: MA, 1988-2012 (Box 16, Folder 3-4)
    Includes correspondence with Clarence Major and Lynn Manning.
  - Correspondence: Lynn Manning, 1982-1984 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: MA-ME, 1981-2013 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: MI-E. Ethelbert Miller, 1975-2011 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: E. Ethelbert Miller, 1985-2013 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: MI, 1986-2008 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: MO, 1977-2011 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: MO-MS, 1976-2013 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    Includes correspondence with Tracie Morris.
  - Correspondence: MU, 1985-2007 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    Includes correspondence with Carol Muske-Dukes.
  - Correspondence: Donna Mungen, 1983-2002 (Box 43, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence: NA, 1981-2007 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: NA-National Endowment for the Arts, 1986-2011 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: National Endowment for the Arts, 1994-2009 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Paul Nelson, 1998-2010 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    File contains one 1/8 inch audio cassette. Audiovisual materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. To review these audiovisual materials, you must notify the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk in advance of your visit.
  - Correspondence: F.A. Nettlebeck, 1979-2012 (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence: NE-NI, 1975-2007 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    Includes correspondence with Maxine Chernoff and Paul Hoover regarding New American Writing submissions, and submissions correspondence with The New Yorker.
  - Correspondence: NO-NU, 1982-2008 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    Includes correspondence with Giovanni Singleton regarding nocturnes submissions.
  - Correspondence: OB-OS, 1979-2009 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: OS-OZ, 1985-2007 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    Includes letter of complaint to editors of The Oxford Companion to African American Literature.
  - Correspondence: The Parness Agency, 1991-1994 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: PEN Center USA, 1980-2006 (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence: Poetry Connexion (KPFK), 1984-1995 (Box 22, Folder 3-4)
  - Correspondence: P and misc., 1986-2005 (Box 184, Folder 14)
    THIS ITEM HAS BEEN DIGITIZED. Please contact the reference desk for details on arranging access.
  - Correspondence: PA, 1997 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: PA-PI, 1978-2006 (Box 184, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: PI-PL, 2005-2007 (Box 184, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: PE-PO, 2005-2012 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    Includes materials relating to Coleman's run for poet laureate of Los Angeles.
  - Correspondence: PO, 1974-2012 (Box 23, Folder 1-2, Box 22, Folder 6-7)
  - Correspondence: PO-PR, 1985-2004 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: PR-PU, 1985-2010 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    Includes Pushcart Prize nominations.
  - Correspondence: QU-RA, 1992-2011 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: RA-Red Hen Press (Kate Gale), 1998-2010 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: RE-Sylvia Rosen, 1982-2010 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Sylvia Rosen-RO, 1992-2012 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    Includes letter from Luis Rodriguez.
  - Correspondence: Rita Rosenkrantz (agent), 1990-2001 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: RO-SA, 1977-2012 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Natasha Saje, 2008-2012 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    Contains Saje's long interview with Coleman.
  - Correspondence: SA-Carol Schwalberg, 1983-2009 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Carol Schwalberg, 1997-2013 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Carol Schwalberg-SE, 1975-2013 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: SC-SM, 1985-2003 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    Includes correspondence with Patricia Smith.
  - Correspondence: SE-SH, 1982-2010 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: SH-ST, 1995-2012 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    Includes letter to Evie Shockley.
  - Correspondence: SN-SO, 1994-2003 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    Includes correspondence with Alan Snitow regarding his documentary Blacks and Jews, which Coleman participated in the making of.
  - Correspondence: SO-SY, 1997-2003 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    Includes letter to Gerald Stern.
  - Correspondence: ST-TA, 1995-2013 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    Includes correspondence with Bobbi Sykes and Amber Tamblyn.
  - Correspondence: Sandra Stanley, 1999 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    Correspondence regarding Stanley's entry on Coleman for the Dictionary of Literary Biography.
  - Correspondence: Bobbi Sykes, 1982-2001 (Box 49, Folder 1, Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Bobbi Sykes (Australia Trip), 1986-1997 (Box 51, Folder 2-3)
  - Correspondence: Bobbi Sykes (Interview), 1985 (Box 49, Folder 2-4)
  - Correspondence: TA, 1986-2009 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    Includes correspondence with Amber Tamblyn and correspondence regarding the 1999 World Heavyweight Championship Poetry Bout in Taos (Coleman vs. Sherman Alexie).
  - Correspondence: TE-TH, 1983-2011 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    Includes correspondence with Lisa Teasley.
  - Correspondence: TH-TI, 1975-2009 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: TR, 1983-2012 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Truong Tran (Letters to Poets), 2003-2008 (Box 52, Folder 6-7)
    Contains correspondence between Coleman and Tran collected in an anthology, Letters to Poets (ed. Dana Teen Lomax).
  - Correspondence: TR-TU, 1986-2007 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    Includes correspondence with Quincy Troupe.
  - Correspondence: UCLA (special collections), 2012-2013 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: UG-UR, 1984-2005 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    Includes correspondence with David Ulin and Tony Magistrale.
  - Correspondence: University of Pittsburgh Press, 2002-2013 (Box 27, Folder 3-5)
  - Correspondence: UT-VO, 1987-2011 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: WA, 1988-2012 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    Includes correspondence with Diane Wakoski and Anne Waldman.
  - Correspondence: WA-WE, 1981-2012 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: WE-WI, 1989-2009 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    Includes letter to Cornel West.
  - Correspondence: WI, 1995-2011 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Jokie Wilson, 1992-2013 (Box 29, Folder 1-2, Box 28, Folder 5, Box 184, Folder 17)
    ITEM IN BOX 184 HAS BEEN DIGITIZED. Please contact the reference desk for details on arranging access.
  - Correspondence: Jokie Wilson (art), 1994-1996 (Box 44, Folder 5-6)
  - Correspondence: WI-WO, 1985-2009 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    Includes correspondence with Murray Wolfe.
  - Correspondence: WO, 1987-2012 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    Includes correspondence with Terry Wolverton.
  - Correspondence: WO-Gail Wronsky, 1990-2012 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: X-ZI, 1981-2011 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: ZI-ZYZZYVA, 1985-2006 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1969-1976 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1979 (Box 185, Folder 1-2, Box 30, Folder 4)
    General
    Items in Box 185 were treated for mold. Use caution when handling.
  - Correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 30, Folder 5-6)
  - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1983 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 55, Folder 2-3)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 32, Folder 2, Box 54)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1989 (Box 32, Folder 1, Box 33, Folder 3-7, Box 31, Folder 2-7)
  - Correspondence, 1991-1999 (Box 33, Folder 2-6, Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2000-2009 (Box 34, Folder 2-5, Box 37, Folder 1-7, Box 36, Folder 1-6, Box 38, Folder 5-6, Folder 1-2, Box 35, Folder 1-5)